<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Figuring \w+ out</title>
	<subtitle></subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com"/>
	<updated>2023-08-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com</id>
	<author>
		<name>Christopher Lopes</name>
		<email></email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Why not to ask doctors for their advice</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-08-30-why-not-to-ask-doctors-for-their-advice/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-08-30-why-not-to-ask-doctors-for-their-advice/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-danger&quot;&gt;The danger &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-08-30-why-not-to-ask-doctors-for-their-advice/#the-danger&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While not tho focus of the EconTalk episode &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.econtalk.org/vinay-prasad-on-cancer-screening/&quot;&gt;Vinay Prasad on Cancer Screening&lt;/a&gt; Russ Roberts raises the dilema of asking your doctor what they would do when facing a health care situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…where there&#39;s uncertainty and a financial stake, it&#39;s often helpful to ask the doctor, let&#39;s say you&#39;re helping your mother or dealing with some health crisis. You say to the doctor, &amp;quot;Well, if this was your mother, what would you do?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with asking the doctor who performs these procedures is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But of course, if you&#39;re doing these procedures, you&#39;ve probably convinced yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often lean on the advice of those providing a service. I am overly sensitive to the possibility of being sold something. But I usually do not take into account the fact that the people providing the service are biased. They have a strong belief in the service they provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-illustration&quot;&gt;Further illustration &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-08-30-why-not-to-ask-doctors-for-their-advice/#further-illustration&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dilemma reminds me of the EconTalk episode &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.econtalk.org/megan-mcardle-on-the-oedipus-trap/&quot;&gt;Megan McArdle on the Oedipus Trap&lt;/a&gt;. In this episode they discuss Walter Freeman, who crafted the technique of using a pick like device inserted through the eye socket to perform lobotomies. He spent the end of his life tracking down former patients trying to confirm his belief that his procedure was beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes sense he would be so firmly rooted in believing his procedure was beneficial. To believe otherwise means he would have to come to terms with performing tremendous harm and destroying the lives of many. His life provides a great example of why asking your doctor what they would do in your position may be a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-reflection&quot;&gt;In reflection &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-08-30-why-not-to-ask-doctors-for-their-advice/#in-reflection&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I trust an authority then I place a high value on their guidance. I believe their guidance is often accurate. But at times they may overprescribe their service, because that is what they have persuaded themselves to be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still believe it is wise to ask for guidance from an authority, but I&#39;ll be seconding guessing doing so and examining more closely what they have to say.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Ask vs guess culture at work</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-08-20-ask-vs-guess-culture-at-work/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-08-20-ask-vs-guess-culture-at-work/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the article &lt;a href=&quot;https://jeanhsu.substack.com/p/ask-vs-guess-culture&quot;&gt;Ask vs guess culture&lt;/a&gt; I appreciated the attention drawn to the conflict between the typical &amp;quot;ask&amp;quot; culture at work and the more typical &amp;quot;guess&amp;quot; culture in personal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a high level, western corporate work operates almost entirely in ask culture. But people working at these companies often operate in or were raised in guess culture, which as you might expect, is ripe for feeling misunderstood and frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, we experienced an after-hours outage at work. I work later than everyone else, so I was the only one around to notice it. I could determine that the issue was outside my typical role. I communicated about the issues in the department&#39;s messaging channel. A member of another team, who is more closely connected to the issue, responded. We continued to investigate, but we weren&#39;t making much progress. He raised the issue in the IT messaging channel. He was instructed to call in so the appropriate personal could be notified, which he did. The person notified was able to quickly determine the issue and work to resolve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is challenging for me to &amp;quot;ask&amp;quot;. I don&#39;t want to bother someone else, especially if I&#39;m responsible for doing something. In the story above, I believe I eventually could have determined the problem, but I now know I would not have been able to resolve it. Even still, I feel obligated to diagnosis the problem so that when I need to make a request I know they need to be bothered and that I have reduced my request to the minimal amount. I observed this in myself in the midst of the outage, but I still resisted asking. I&#39;ve known this about myself for most of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel the article was helpful in that it normalized the conflict within me and has provided me rational for reaching out and asking, especially when I know assistance is needed. I realize I need to be prepared for the kind of response I receive, because it also will be different from when I make a request from a well researched guess. They may quickly decline, by other askers. Or I may impose on them, other guessers. I may feel hurt. I may feel shame. I may feel like a failure. But I also may feel camaraderie. Someone else may feel important. It all may establish a better community.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The fall of poetry</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-08-08-the-fall-of-poetry/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-08-08-the-fall-of-poetry/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I found myself taking notes while listening to the EconTalk episode &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.econtalk.org/erik-hoel-on-consciousness-free-will-and-the-limits-of-science/&quot;&gt;Erik Hoel on Consciousness, Free Will, and the Limits of
Science&lt;/a&gt;.
The interview discussed our intrinsic and extrinsic understandings of ourselves and the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the topics discussed was whether it is possible for the brain to understand itself, and
whether neuroscience can or should unite the extrinsic and intrinsic. This was an interesting
conversation, but it is not the focus of my writing, so I will not comment on it. However, I do
recommend listening to the whole interview, as it raises many interesting points to contemplate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another topic discussed was the growth of human intrinsic understanding. This is the section of the
interview that is of interest to me here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we think about ourselves is not constant. This means that the way we consume ancient art and
literature is not the same today as when it was created. For example, strong emotional reactions are
rare in ancient literature. This is because a rich language for describing our minds did not exist
at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot say I enjoy poetry. For much of my life I did not value poetry. However, in the past couple
of years I have been moved to desire to value poetry, although I have mostly been unsuccessful in
this pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interview, the host states that poetry is a way to express things that we don&#39;t always have
the words for. As someone who rarely is able to find the words to express what I&#39;m thinking or
feeling this description of poetry leads me to desire it even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, perhaps our increased intrinsic understanding and rich language is a reason why poetry has
fallen out of favor. In ancient times, our intrinsic knowledge and language were not sufficient to
communicate what we were feeling inside. Poetry filled that gap, and was therefore highly valued. It
was commonly written, memorized, and recited. Today, we understand ourselves to a greater depth and
have a rich language for communicating, which has led to a diminished role of poetry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe there are many reasons poetry has lost it&#39;s luster, but this was a novel reason for me,
which I wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Lessons from my dog on courage</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-06-16-lessons-from-my-dog-on-courage/"/>
		<updated>2023-06-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-06-16-lessons-from-my-dog-on-courage/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m sitting in my backyard enjoying the afternoon. It warmed my heart as I
watched my dog sitting in the grass keeping observant watch over the street.
But then the thought came to me, eventually the day will come I&#39;ll need to put
him down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This caused me to reminisce about the movies I watched growing up featuring a
dog and his boy. The two prominent movies were Where the Red Fern Grows and Old
Yeller. In both movies the dogs courageously protect against a predator. I
suppose not all dogs would do so, but I&#39;m pretty sure my dog would, based upon
past behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me humans used to do so as well. In battles they would march in
lines while being picked off. Or rush out of their trenches directly toward
enemy gun fire. I don&#39;t think most humans would do either of those today. I
wonder why. And I wonder if this change is desirable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does seem desirable that we seemingly have the ability to choose not to. We
are not obligated by needing to defend our communities, whatever they be in
their many forms. But in what other ways are we now failing our communities by
choosing to not do the hard thing. In what ways have we not developed the
character or the relationships that would have compelled us to do those hard
things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand I&#39;m grateful I&#39;ve had an easy life in which I have not had to go
through extremely challenging experiences. But on the other hand I wonder what
kind of person I would now be if I did. I don&#39;t want to romanticize this. The
trauma formed also greatly alters life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We each face difficult experiences. It is harder to choose to face them if you
are not compelled to do so. But volunteering to face them is the best of both
worlds. The trauma is not as significant and it still brings about growth.
Please let me choose to step into them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything I need
A life of relaxation
A weak man I am&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Lessons from my dog on meditation</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-06-12-lessons-from-my-dog-on-meditation/"/>
		<updated>2023-06-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-06-12-lessons-from-my-dog-on-meditation/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently read about three meditation practices, the purpose of which was to help calm the brain by
paying attention to the body in the present. That got me thinking about the my dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, dogs are focused on the present. Whatever the moment brings is what they&#39;re completely
immersed in. Whether is is time to eat, play, sleep, or be on squirrel patrol, that is where he
fully is. My dog excels at meditating to be present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I&#39;m focused on the present but often I&#39;m reliving the past or running scenarios about the
future. As an example, this morning I woke up two hours early. I laid there knowing I would not go
back to sleep, but hoping. I eventually got up and wrote this post. Initially I was concerned about
the future, how I&#39;d feel today. I&#39;m still concerned. But eventually I cajoled myself to get up and
take action on some of the thoughts running through my head, this post being one item. It was only
while I was typing this that I realized by typing this I was being present. I am presently doing
what the reality of the &amp;quot;now&amp;quot; actually is. I need meditation to help me do what the present calls
for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, when an exciting event occurs my dog has great difficulty restraining himself. When we have
guests come to our house my dog is instructed to sit on his bed and wait. He mostly can do this. But
as he waits he still whines with excitement and dances his front legs, raring to go say hi. There
are many other scenarios he also experiences significant challenges restraining himself, and
unfortunately is only able to do so for so long before he is overcome and fails. My dog desperately
needs mediation to bridle his reactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also overcome. I can restrain my body but I have great difficulty in restraining my mind. I
realize I need a very similar training as my dog. To not unhealthily be focused on something, which
only consumes us to our own determinant. Both of us need meditation to help us let go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>MDN sponsored content… I&#39;m still hesitant to pay for things</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-05-30-mdn-sponsored-content-i-am-still%20hesitant-to-pay-for-things/"/>
		<updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-05-30-mdn-sponsored-content-i-am-still%20hesitant-to-pay-for-things/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/blog/welcome-to-the-MDN-blog/#tutorials_guides_and_sponsored_content&quot;&gt;MDN&#39;s welcome blog post they included a section about sponsored
content&lt;/a&gt;.
Unsurprisingly my immediate felt reaction is disgust. Instead of unbiased helpful content companies
will now be able to purchase the persuasion of developers. I want to throw up my hands and give up
on the internet. To mourn what it was. What it could have been. In most scenarios companies need to
make more and more income. In Mozilla&#39;s case it may be more about keeping the lights on, at least
partially. So can I really blame them? I don&#39;t use MDN often. But I do use Firefox. Yet I don&#39;t
support them financially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there is search. These days search is filled with sponsored results. Yes, even though it&#39;s
called Google Ads I see the usage of &amp;quot;Sponsored&amp;quot; in my Google search results. I&#39;ve been using Duck
Duck Go for many years. In the end I&#39;m not sure using it is much better, other than it is not
Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been numerous alternative search services available the past few years. Most leverage an
existing search provider. The alternative I&#39;ve been following is Kagi. I created an account last
year, but I&#39;ve yet to upgrade to premium. I keep telling myself I should upgrade. We need viable
choices. I have my reasons not to upgrade, or maybe I should say my excuses not to. Ultimately I&#39;m
frugal. I&#39;m cheap. I want something for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many things we make use of today. It feels overwhelming to pay for each of these
things. But these services need to survive one way or another. Most services will only survive for a
short lifetime altruistically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, I stand at the threshold, being upset about where I stand but not stepping across.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Reflections on the article: Continuous growth is cancer</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-03-04-reflections-on-continuous-growth-is-cancer/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-03-04-reflections-on-continuous-growth-is-cancer/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning I read the article &lt;a href=&quot;https://christianheilmann.com/2023/03/03/continuous-growth-is-cancer/&quot;&gt;Continuous growth is cancer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of building a sustainable work environment with sensible compensation, the system favours&lt;br /&gt;
continuous growth – something that isn&#39;t possible in a world of limited resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several aspects of this post resonated with me. I recognize cycles of growth are important and
necessary. But it seems to me growth is our primary objective. It makes sense. It&#39;s an easy metric
which shows we are succeeding, at least at first look and for the moment. Perhaps it provides
positive emotions, because the pursuit of growth triggers dopamine. But growth cannot continue
continuously forever. The pursuit of growth is often shortsighted which can lead to detrimental
consequences. Cancer in someways in an apt analogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fetish we have for growth is starting to annoy me. If your career doesn&#39;t progress every half
year, you’re a failure. If your product doesn&#39;t double user numbers each quarter, it gets
canceled. If you don’t show any interest in advancing up the career ladder, but instead focus on
your job, you’ll get asked why that is and pushed into booster processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been at my current organization as it has more than doubled in size. They have managed growth
well. Be there are aspects of who we were which have been lost, which I mourn. It&#39;s not the same
place. I&#39;m grateful for what the organization has provided me. But I&#39;m also discouraged, saddened
and frustrated. The organization believes growth is always necessary and always what we should be
pursuing. It supports you in your career, as long as your career is moving up the management ladder,
which I am not interested in. Even though I have done much of the leading which has brought my
department to where we currently are I am left unrecognized as others pass me by on their pursuit of
&amp;quot;leadership&amp;quot;. When I inquire about other forms of leadership the only response I receive is sorry,
we&#39;re not big enough to support other forms of leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe we should grow in our mindfulness and humanity and not only in numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am left feeling we get our priorities out of wack. Others have been sounding the trumpet about the
shortsightedness of our culture today. What is the solution to this? Is there a different value
which can guide us? If so what risk and impact must be accepted to follow it? Are we too big to
change?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>I am a storyteller</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-29-i-am-a-storyteller/"/>
		<updated>2023-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-29-i-am-a-storyteller/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-desire&quot;&gt;The desire &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-29-i-am-a-storyteller/#the-desire&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I read a question by someone asking how to become a better storyteller. This question
resonates with me. I feel I lack the ability to tell a good story. I&#39;m not sure where the desire to
be a good storyteller comes from. The place I first identify is to be warmer and more entertaining in
social situations. But I don&#39;t know if the desire is to be looked well upon, to soothe my own social
anxiety, for the benefit of the other, to create a better community, or some other reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-recommendation&quot;&gt;The recommendation &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-29-i-am-a-storyteller/#the-recommendation&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The questioner received several answers. The book &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.storygrid.com/books/&quot;&gt;Story Grid&lt;/a&gt;, along with its associated material.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://channel101.fandom.com/wiki/Story_Structure_101:_Super_Basic_Shit&quot;&gt;Dan Harmon&#39;s story structure&lt;/a&gt; was also recommended. I read through the structure. It provided a
good framing for me. It will require practice for me to place stories I tell into this format. But
having a structure provides me confidence in being able to craft a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But of course I need a source for stories I tell. The best way to generate stories is to live a life
full of stories. As an introvert my experiences are minimal and not very exciting, so I don&#39;t feel
like I have a plentiful source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;everyday-is-a-story&quot;&gt;Everyday is a story &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-29-i-am-a-storyteller/#everyday-is-a-story&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stories, however, I don&#39;t think need to be as exciting as what I feel they need to be. Yes, if
something eventful happens the story is more engaging. But we relate to lots of things which happen
in life. Additionally, I can be creative with my stories. I can make up things which happen,
similar to jokes. Or start from something I observe. Or start from something which happens but then
continue forward in a creative way, how it played out in my head. All of these sources can be
entertaining and communicate about my perspective, the way I see things, think about things.
Therefore being creative doesn&#39;t mean it&#39;s empty sharing. The story still contains meaning. It&#39;s
communicating a different aspect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-stories-we-tell-ourselves&quot;&gt;The stories we tell ourselves &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-29-i-am-a-storyteller/#the-stories-we-tell-ourselves&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I felt sleepy as I was sitting during church. As we were walking to the car afterwards
my wife asked if I was tired. I said I was resting as I was listening. She said I was head bobbing
during church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we drove away I felt embarrassed and wondering who else noticed. Along with this feeling I
started thinking why I was sleepy. I began having conversations with others in my head telling them
why I was sleepy and so why it was reasonable I was head bobbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was at this moment I realized I was telling myself a story. I&#39;ve learned we are constantly telling
ourselves stories. This was a good example on how this plays out in life. It reminds me of the study
in which the corpus callosum was severed in people who experience seizures in order to prevent
seizures from occurring. An interesting result was found which has been named the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Left-brain_interpreter&quot;&gt;left-brain
interpreter&lt;/a&gt;. When the field of vision is restricted between the left and right eyes then if the
right eye is shown something the left brain will make up what it believes to be a reasonable
explanation about the action which occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the left-brain interpreter will nonetheless construct a contrived explanation for the action,
unaware of the instruction the right brain had received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been determined we all experience this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drive to seek explanations and provide interpretations is a general human trait, and the
left-brain interpreter can be seen as the glue that attempts to hold the story together, in order
to provide a sense of coherence to the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was then I realized that I am already an expert storyteller. My brain is constantly telling
myself stories. Believable stories. I am a storyteller. It&#39;s not a foreign practice. Therefore
relax, trust your instincts and dive in!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>We teach failure is to be feared</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-19-we-teach-failure-is-to-be-feared/"/>
		<updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-19-we-teach-failure-is-to-be-feared/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-fear-of-failure-impacts-me&quot;&gt;How fear of failure impacts me &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-19-we-teach-failure-is-to-be-feared/#how-fear-of-failure-impacts-me&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve carried the fear of failure for as long as I can remember. There&#39;s no area of my life where this fear does not reach. As I&#39;ve grown older I believe I understand this emotion better. That I can recognize it and understand why I am experiencing it. But it doesn&#39;t mean I&#39;m not overcome by it and that it has an undesirable impact in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One significant area of my life this fear has dominated me has been in school. One positive aspect to this fear is that it motivated me to do well in school. But the negative side of it is that it caused me to focus on what it would take to get the mark. Even though I&#39;m a curious person this part of me was sacrificed at the alter of fear. I don&#39;t know if today I&#39;d do much better letting this fear control me. Yet I long to be in an environment where I can be curious and explore. Where the learning process is to be enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I was in a discussion about high school students enrolled in Running Start. Sometimes they complete everything needed to graduate but because of timelines they are still finishing the Running Start classes. But at this point it doesn&#39;t matter how they do in the class. It doesn&#39;t impact their high school record and it won&#39;t impact their college record. When students are in this position they frequently slack off and stop working. I imagine I would have kept working for the grade, out of fear of failure. But I wondered, would I have been able to experience this scenario as freeing? Since the grade would not have had any impact would I have been able to let my curiosity out and finally enjoy the learning process?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-we-teach-failure-is-to-be-feared&quot;&gt;How we teach failure is to be feared &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-19-we-teach-failure-is-to-be-feared/#how-we-teach-failure-is-to-be-feared&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://freakonomics.com/podcast/is-gaming-good-for-you/&quot;&gt;Episode 76 of the podcast People I Mostly Admire&lt;/a&gt; with guest &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jane_McGonigal&quot;&gt;Jane McGonigal&lt;/a&gt; of the book &lt;a href=&quot;https://janemcgonigal.com/my-book/&quot;&gt;SuperBetter&lt;/a&gt; compared video games to our educational system. When playing a video game it is okay if you fail because you are able keep trying, playing over and over, as long as you want. But in school you typically have one try. You don&#39;t get to retake a test. Relearn the material. This makes for an &amp;quot;overly punitive system&amp;quot; in which instead of embracing and enjoying a challenge we are anxious and fear the failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could not have finish school soon enough. In university I was offered the opportunity to continue on in graduate school and teach. I was approached be several professors. I dismissed them all immediately. I did not enjoy school. There&#39;s so much I lost by not being able to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-consequences-of-teaching-failure-is-to-be-feared&quot;&gt;The consequences of teaching failure is to be feared &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-19-we-teach-failure-is-to-be-feared/#the-consequences-of-teaching-failure-is-to-be-feared&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is understandable how we&#39;ve ended up in a punitive educational system. But because we do operate under such a system what we lose is substantial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear of failures prevents many of us from starting things, learning things, and receiving correction well. This blog post for example. It is not researched. It is not thought out. Instead I am merely shaping my thoughts as I go. And it makes me wonder, there is failure in this approach. Perhaps if it was thought out and researched it would be more persuasive. That it would present a better impression of myself. But by that reasoning I probably would never write anything because I&#39;d know I could always research it more. Think about it more. Wisdom is in understanding this line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But having a society where its people have been taught through fear leads to a society of people who feel bad about themselves. We give up. We focus on the wrong thing. There is a tremendous amount of potential which will never be realized. That is lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing the educational system isn&#39;t going to happen overnight, but maybe eventually. In the meantime I desire to be the kind of person where I communicate failure differently in the relationships I am, to encourage others to keep trying instead of fearing. To enjoy taking on hard things and challenged by failure, instead of being anxious and fearing failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Using devcontainers with VS Code and GitHub Codespaces</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-16-devcontainers/"/>
		<updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-16-devcontainers/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-beginning%3A-creating-a-blazor-wasm-application-on-both-windows-and-linux&quot;&gt;The beginning: Creating a Blazor WASM application on both Windows and Linux &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-16-devcontainers/#the-beginning%3A-creating-a-blazor-wasm-application-on-both-windows-and-linux&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a Windows machine at work but a Linux machine at home. I do .Net development at work.
Although I&#39;d prefer to development in a different ecosystem at home it is still helpful to be
able to experiment and do some .Net development at home. In theory this should now be possible.
However I always seem to run into issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of my learning related to work I decided to create a simple shopping list application using
an &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/static-web-apps&quot;&gt;Azure Static Website Application&lt;/a&gt;, SWA. I&#39;ve also wanted to try out WASM, so off I went starting my project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-create-the-project-and-the-azure-resources&quot;&gt;How to create the project and the Azure resources &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-16-devcontainers/#how-to-create-the-project-and-the-azure-resources&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also was interested in learning how to integrate the &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/developer/azure-developer-cli/&quot;&gt;Azure Developer CLI&lt;/a&gt; (azd). There currently isn&#39;t a
template to start from for the project type I wanted to create. Therefore I started out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Azure-Samples/todo-csharp-sql-swa-func&quot;&gt;azd C#
Static Web App template&lt;/a&gt; to learn from. When I tried provisioning Azure resources stating a
resource was not available in the region I selected. But it did not report which resource it was!
Thankfully I had recently tried deploying an Azure SQL DB recently and remembered it was not
available in the region I normally use. I selected a different region and tried again. Same type of
failure. I was able to eventually determine which other resource it was not happy with in the region
I selected. Finally I was able to successfully provision Azure resources. But a couple days later I
realized I should have looked at the resources the template was creating because the Azure SQL DB
quickly spent all of my credits and locked my account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not give up. I pushed forward and went through the process of customizing the template for my
project. There&#39;s a lot in these templates however. So the process took time as I tried to simplify
the template for my project. It was an error prone and lengthy process. Thankfully I never felt
completely stuck and so was able to finally provision all of the resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my Blazor WASM project from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/staticwebdev/blazor-starter&quot;&gt;Blazor Starter template&lt;/a&gt;. However when I tried to deploy
the application it failed. The resolution was not obvious. Perhaps WASM is not supported by azd for
SWA&#39;s. I was exhausted. At this point I just wanted something which worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SWA&#39;s have their own CLI. It&#39;s a convenient way to create, develop and deploy SWAs. Therefore I next
tried this route. However I immediately ran into errors. I don&#39;t remember what they were. I didn&#39;t
spend time attempting to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a final fallback I used the built in GitHub Actions to deploy the SWA. Thankfully this worked
without issue. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pulled-in-again-with-dev-containers&quot;&gt;Pulled in again with Dev Containers &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-16-devcontainers/#pulled-in-again-with-dev-containers&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azd is still in beta. A recent update included azd usage from &lt;a href=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-january-2023-release/#use-the-azure-developer-cli-in-github-codespaces&quot;&gt;within GitHub Codespaces&lt;/a&gt;, which uses
&lt;a href=&quot;https://containers.dev/&quot;&gt;Dev Containers&lt;/a&gt;. I was familiar with the usage of Dev Containers with VS Code but had never used
them before. I figure now was a great time incorporate them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how to begin? There&#39;s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/devcontainers/devcontainer-cli&quot;&gt;Dev Container CLI&lt;/a&gt;. Yikes! That&#39;s more than I wanted to dig into.
There must be a simpler way to get going. How about a template to work from? This looks like a
simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/vscode-remote-try-dotnet/blob/main/.devcontainer/devcontainer.json&quot;&gt;Dev Container Template&lt;/a&gt;. I started out with it, and added in my VS Code extensions, which
was what I thought would be the primary benefit of setting up a Dev Container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to launch a Codespace. But VS Code was recommending extensions which I thought I had
already specified. Unfortunately I had a couple typos and I didn&#39;t notice any messages indicating
this. I was able to figure out the issue. Extensions installed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-dotnettools.blazorwasm-companion&quot;&gt;Blazor WASM Debugging extension&lt;/a&gt;. It reports it cannot be used in a Dev Container. Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And wait, azd is not installed in the container. I watched the video embedded in the azd
announcement, saw the template they were using for the demo, and examined their Dev Container
configuration. They use a Dockerfile and specify several images in their configuration. I guess it&#39;s
going to be more complicated than I had hoped. Well, at least now I have another example template
to work from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changes required were not significant and I was up and running soon. First step, logging in. My
user name is the same between my enterprise work and MSDN work accounts. Try as I may I cannot
log into the MSDN account. It turns out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Azure/azure-dev/releases/tag/azure-dev-cli_0.5.0-beta.2&quot;&gt;new version of azd introduced this bug&lt;/a&gt;. I wonder what
version is installed in the Dev Container. The timing of the report of the bug and its resolution
worked out for me. A fix was quickly in place for me to use. But now I can login but it doesn&#39;t know
about my Azure subscription. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Azure/azure-dev/issues/1398&quot;&gt;A new issue has already been created&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;local-dev-container-usage&quot;&gt;Local Dev Container usage &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-16-devcontainers/#local-dev-container-usage&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now every time I start up VS Code it asks if I want to open the project in the Dev Container. That&#39;s
sort of annoying. How can I always just open it in the Dev Container? After looking around the Dev
Container should have an &lt;em&gt;open&lt;/em&gt; command. But I don&#39;t see that command. There are GitHub issues
about this command is missing after an update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a whim I uninstalled the Dev Container CLI and instead installed the tool through VS Code and
added the path to the tool in my shell profile. This version does have the &lt;em&gt;open&lt;/em&gt; command. I&#39;m
calling it good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2023-01-16-devcontainers/#conclusion&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like it has been a long journey. Longer than it should have been. When things follow the
predetermined path then they work great out of the box. But if you need something different then
prepared to figure things out as you go. It is in beta. And this is all part of the learning
process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I need to try develop using the Dev Container and determine if this process provides added
value, hopefully making it more seamless to develop in Linux and across platforms: Linux, Windows
and Codespaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The core of what it is to love someone</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-21-the-core-of-what-it-is-to-love-someone/"/>
		<updated>2021-11-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-21-the-core-of-what-it-is-to-love-someone/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-excerpt&quot;&gt;The excerpt &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-21-the-core-of-what-it-is-to-love-someone/#the-excerpt&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An excerpt from &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/DLg2Q0daphE?t=2700&quot;&gt;Jordan Peterson&#39;s interview with John Vervaeke&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of Rhineland Mysticism was this kind of receptivity, you have to make a space so that the son of God can be born within you. And again, not to be irreligious, but for me to to love my partner is to cultivate that kind of receptivity, a space in which she can be within me, and I don&#39;t mean in any purely romantic metaphorical sense. What I mean is she finds a purchase within me whereby she can realize herself, in both senses of the word realize. And she can come to trust that that space that place of realization will always be available for her. And she can come to rely on it. A place which she can transcend herself when she needs to. And being committed to that and finding that inseparably bound up with my own project of trying to realize who I am. That&#39;s for me the core of what it is to love somebody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll let the excerpt stand for itself, the link to the interview is provided to for those who desire
to learn more about the excerpt and what more precisely he is expressing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-reflection&quot;&gt;The reflection &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-21-the-core-of-what-it-is-to-love-someone/#the-reflection&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The words &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vervaeke_john&quot;&gt;Vervaeke&lt;/a&gt; used to describe the core of love struck me. His articulation of love evoked
a visceral response in me. Poetry. I desire this, both for myself and for my partner. Yes, this is
what it means to love someone. Well, it is one expression of it. A sacred, safe, trusted place
within myself for another. Bound up forever together as we journey, to learn about ourself, about
ourselves. I need that. I want to provide that. A vow to make. A commitment to each other. A north
star to guide our relationship as we wander, get off track, and find our way back. By the grace of
God may I. May we.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-to-where-it-started&quot;&gt;Back to where it started &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-21-the-core-of-what-it-is-to-love-someone/#back-to-where-it-started&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vervaeke is borrowing language describing our relationship with God. Space within us so that the son
of God is born within us. After concluding the previous section, where I invoke the grace of God, my
thoughts are only complete by circling back and noting this space we allow in us seems contingent on
us first having this space in us which God can take hold and grow, so that his grace works out of us
from within. I don&#39;t know how else we will be able to trust and maintain safe spaces while we do
come to know ourselves and each other. To have a space within us where another is able to reside in
some ways seems like a organ transplant. It is only with medication our body will not reject the new
organ. It is with the grace of God I will not reject another as I maintain a space with myself for
them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the grace of God&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Computer backups</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-13-computer-backups/"/>
		<updated>2021-11-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-13-computer-backups/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;neglect&quot;&gt;Neglect &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-13-computer-backups/#neglect&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw the topic of backups come up again on Hacker News. A couple years ago I set up both Duplicacy
and Restic. I was going to run both and then compare them. Instead of setting up a schedule I would
run a script to kick off the backups. I don&#39;t remember the details but I found Duplicacy easier to
keep up with so I dropped running Restic fairly quick. I don&#39;t remember how long I kept up with the
backups run by Duplicacy but it fail by the wayside at some point. At this point I don&#39;t even
remember how I was running them. Considering all of this of course I decided to start all over. This
time I decided to try &lt;a href=&quot;https://kopia.io/&quot;&gt;Kopia&lt;/a&gt;, foolishly believing a new tool will of course fix my issues of
neglecting backups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-13-computer-backups/#getting-started&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installation was simple in Arch: &lt;code&gt;yay -S kopia&lt;/code&gt;. There are a number of go modules which are
downloaded. I did not see a package for the KopiaUI which was disappointing because I was going for
easy. But the CLI is preferable anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I followed their Getting Started guide. The first example is using the file system. Probably the
simplest use case, so let&#39;s try it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia repository create filesystem --path /home/my-user/kopia-backup
kopia snapshot create ~/Documents
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It prompted for a password when creating the repository and then quickly created the snapshot.
Simple indeed. Let&#39;s take a look at the snapshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia snapshot list
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;policies&quot;&gt;Policies &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-13-computer-backups/#policies&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I want to change some of those policies, like which files to ignore. Let&#39;s take a look at
the current default policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia policy show --global
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, lets ignore some directories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia policy set --add-ignore .node_modules/ --global
kopia policy set --add-ignore .git/ --global
kopia policy show --global
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent! I&#39;m was thinking about changing the retention policies but perhaps it&#39;s better to keep
the defaults for now, at least on the file system repository. But for reference the command to
change the policy is simple to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia policy set --keep-monthly 10 --global
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My preference is to use compression though. Maybe not so important for the file system repository
but a feature it will be helpful to try out, hopefully it will help verify I won&#39;t have issues
running it on other repositories. The documentation recommends running a benchmark to help determine
which algorithm to use. I tried running the benchmark on a couple files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia benchmark compression --data-file=book.pdf
kopia benchmark compression --data-file=data.csv
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much difference in the algorithms for those files. And unsurprisingly it didn&#39;t help the PDF.
The CSV isn&#39;t very large so not much benefit there either. Oh well, I&#39;ll still turn it on and pick
an algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia policy set --compression=pgzip --global
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After enabling it and creating a new snapshot you can view the stats of the snapshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia content stats
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;compression 1.3%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;scheduling-%F0%9F%93%85&quot;&gt;Scheduling 📅 &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-13-computer-backups/#scheduling-%F0%9F%93%85&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, well let&#39;s put the backups on a schedule so they don&#39;t get neglected this time. On Arch one
option is to use &lt;code&gt;systemd-run&lt;/code&gt; to run jobs. I&#39;ll create a little script to run all snapshots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &#39;#!/bin/sh\nkopia snapshot create --all&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bin/kopia-backup.sh
chmod +x ~/.bin/kopia-backup.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I&#39;ll add an entry to run the script hourly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;systemd-run --user --on-calendar=hourly ~/.bin/kopia-backup.sh
systemctl list-timers
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;backblaze&quot;&gt;Backblaze &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-13-computer-backups/#backblaze&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an old Backblaze bucket I was using for backups. I&#39;ll repurpose it for the Kopia backups.
I&#39;ll use environment variables for the Backblaze bucket ID and Key so I can store them elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;export B2_KEY_ID=MY-APPLICATION-ID
export B2_KEY=MY-APPLICATION-KEY
kopia repository create b2 --bucket=tCarbon
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policies do need to be set up for this repository as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia policy set --add-ignore .node_modules/ --global
kopia policy set --add-ignore .git/ --global
kopia policy set --compression=pgzip --global
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great! And now we can start creating snapshots for this repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia snapshot create ~/Documents
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;switching-repositories&quot;&gt;Switching repositories &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-13-computer-backups/#switching-repositories&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If multiple repositories are being used then you need to switch to the appropriate repository before
taking the snapshot. The command to switch back and forth is the same as the initial command when
creating the repository except the command is &lt;code&gt;connect&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;create&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kopia repository connect filesystem --path /home/ciwchris/kopia-backup
kopia repository connect b2 --bucket=tCarbon
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;password-management&quot;&gt;Password management &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-11-13-computer-backups/#password-management&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The password for the repository will need to be entered when connecting. To provide the password
securely in the script I&#39;m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.passwordstore.org/&quot;&gt;pass&lt;/a&gt;. To configure pass I followed &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/flbuddymooreiv/a4f24da7e0c3552942ff&quot;&gt;steps in flbuddymooreiv&#39;s
gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a key to use &lt;code&gt;gpg --gen-key&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieve the public key &lt;code&gt;gpg --list-keys&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the public key to initialize pass: &lt;code&gt;pass init xxxxxxxxxxx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Git support to pass: &lt;code&gt;pass git init&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git support can be handy when adding a remote repo which then can be shared between devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a password for kopia: &lt;code&gt;pass insert kopia/filesystem&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backup script can now be modified to insert the password when connecting to the repository. When
the password is accessed a prompt will be displayed to unlock pass. Once the password for pass has
been entered the password will be retrieved and used in the script to connect to the repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/sh

kopia repository connect filesystem --path /home/ciwchris/kopia-backup -p &amp;quot;$(pass kopia/filesystem)&amp;quot;
kopia snapshot create --all
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar steps can be followed to supply the password for connecting to the Backblaze repository as
well as the Backblaze bucket id and key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it for now. Happy backups! 🤞&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>My approach for writing and managing notes</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-my-approach-for-writing-and-managing-notes/"/>
		<updated>2021-06-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-my-approach-for-writing-and-managing-notes/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-issue&quot;&gt;The issue &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-my-approach-for-writing-and-managing-notes/#the-issue&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the idea of notes. A place to collect all the interesting bits of information which I come in contact with and which flow through my mind. But recording, tracking and sharing them has always become an obstacle. I&#39;ve tried numerous system which I end up using for a short period of time but after the initial excitement is gone a lack of motivation sets in to continue to follow the process of managing and sharing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-to-do-about-this&quot;&gt;What to do about this &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-my-approach-for-writing-and-managing-notes/#what-to-do-about-this&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on this behavior my takeaway was to keep my notes and process as simple as possible. For me this meant creating a text file on each device. When I come across something interesting I open up my &lt;code&gt;everything.md&lt;/code&gt; file in the text editor of choice and add a date for the beginning of the week, if one hasn&#39;t already been recorded, and then paste in the link, text or type out the thought prefixed with tag(s) delineated by colons as demonstrated in this example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Date: 6/13

:shopping:reviews:recommendations: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=27219759
:motivation:range:generalist:specialist:
    - https://www.outsideonline.com/2423015/80-20-rule-beginner-mastery-benefits
    - https://www.cell.com/patterns/fulltext/S2666-3899(21)00064-7
:javascript: https://turriate.com/articles/modern-javascript-everything-you-missed-over-10-years
:introvert: https://thehustle.co/why-introverts-make-great-leaders/
:neovim:vim: https://github.com/nvim-telescope/telescope.nvim
:quote:benjamin:franklin: modest diffidence - https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/7971222-i-retained-only-the-habit-of-expressing-my-self-in
:powershell:ignore: --%
:database:testing: https://tsqlt.org/user-guide/quick-start/
:powershell:git:hook: https://gist.github.com/gowon/a36d7622063bd8567f92342f0462ffc5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not too concerned about the structure of the notes, I want to keep it simple to lessen any friction for recording the information. The only rules I try to follow are including a weekly date, add at least one tag, and always use singular words for tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve mostly used this system successfully for over a year now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-weakness&quot;&gt;The weakness &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-my-approach-for-writing-and-managing-notes/#the-weakness&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My primary issue with this system is that the notes are spread across different devices: work laptop, personal laptop and personal phone. I&#39;ve tried several services to be able to share these files across devices. One major limiting factor in doing so is that my work blocks most file syncing services as well as note taking sites. I therefore need something which is simple, accessible, and doesn&#39;t require much effort to maintain myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;current-solution&quot;&gt;Current solution &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-my-approach-for-writing-and-managing-notes/#current-solution&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use GitHub at work. I have a personal account. Private repositories are now free. I mostly enjoy git. All of these facts make for a simple and convenient system for managing my notes. The primary drawback for me is that the file content will not be encrypted at rest, but that was true before, when the files were a text file sitting on each device. They are still this. And since we trust GitHub with our code at work I therefore feel fine with my notes also sitting on their servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next issue is that I use a work GitHub account with my work name and email address. I wanted any commits made from work to not include this information and instead include my personal information. To enable this I am using &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/docs/git-config#_conditional_includes&quot;&gt;git config conditional includes&lt;/a&gt;. An example version of my &lt;code&gt;gitconfig&lt;/code&gt; contains the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[user]
  name = My Name
  email = my.work.name@example.com
  signingkey = 1234567890abcdef
[includeIf &amp;quot;gitdir:C:/my/note/folder/&amp;quot;]
  path = .gitconfig.personal
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then override the &lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt; settings in the &lt;code&gt;.gitconfig.personal&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[user]
  name = My Name
  email = my.personal.name@example.com
  signingkey =
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shared access to my notes repository with my work GitHub account, and so I am still committing from my work account but at least the information in the commits now contain my personal information. This is still not ideal but is simple and suffices. Maybe eventually I&#39;ll do the work to find a simple approach for managing multiple GitHub accounts on a device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up, how to use GitHub from my phone for cloning the repository and then pulling and pushing commits. I looked at several apps for performing this. Again, I wanted something, so I decided to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://manichord.com/projects/mgit.html&quot;&gt;mgit&lt;/a&gt;. The app generates a ssh key when I then can add as a &amp;quot;Deploy key&amp;quot; to the repository with write access. When using the git protocol for the repository URL in mgit then mgit will use the ssh key it generated to access the repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success and Success!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;potential-issues&quot;&gt;Potential issues &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-my-approach-for-writing-and-managing-notes/#potential-issues&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t intend on committing and pushing up a change to a notes file after every edit. Therefore, I&#39;ve renamed each file, so they are specific to each device. I therefore can forget to commit any edits for a period of time without worry about any conflicts to resolve when I get around to it. Not committing immediately also means a note I took on a different device may not be present when I need it on another device, but the potential cost of needing to keep them in sync currently outweighs the risk of not having a note available when I need it. If I do experience this scenario I am thinking it will be an infrequent and minor inconvenience, especially since I now work from home, and so have all my devices in near proximity most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have multiple files broken out by device I decided now was a good time to also try breaking up the files by years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;everything-personal-2021.md
everything-personal-2020.md
everything-phone-2021.md
everything-phone-2021.md
everything-work-2020.md
everything-work-2020.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have concerns about the benefits in doing this and whether it will be the source of obstacles, primarily ease of searching. But at this point I will already be searching across files, so it is worth a try. It&#39;s easy enough to stitch them back together if it becomes an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Science is peculiar in decision-making</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/"/>
		<updated>2021-06-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-prompt&quot;&gt;The prompt &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/#the-prompt&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggle to make decisions and therefore whenever coming across material on the topic I take note. Recently I was listening to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://biologos.org/podcast-episodes/bill-newsome-neuroscience-faith-free-will&quot;&gt;Language of God podcast with Bill Newsome.&lt;/a&gt; in which they discussed a paper he wrote in 2010, &lt;a href=&quot;https://biologos.org/podcast-episodes/bill-newsome-neuroscience-faith-free-will&quot;&gt;Life of science, life of faith.&lt;/a&gt; Both the podcast and the paper are interesting and so worth the listen and read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;science-is-peculiar&quot;&gt;Science is peculiar &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/#science-is-peculiar&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two points in particular which stood out to me while listening to the podcast which motivated me to read the paper. The first addresses a question he often receives from his colleague concerning the apparent inconsistent approach between the way he approaches his scientific work and his religious life. In the paper he writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both my colleague and my postdoc were struck by the apparent inconsistency in my adoption of religious beliefs without similarly rigorous standards of proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reply is that, yes, the modes of thought in the two domains can be quite different. This is one of the genuine points of tension between science and religion. Importantly, however, the mode that predominates in religious life is the normal mode of evaluation and decision-making in the overall context of human experience. The scientific mode, in contrast, is quite peculiar: it is applicable to a rather narrow range of experience and is generally practiced by a rather small community of professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me this was a moment of enlightenment. I attempt to bring a scientific approach to everything in my life but I struggle greatly to do so. I do not trust my intuition. I do not trust my emotions. I often sink lots of time trying to understand what to think, feel, or do in all areas of my life. I become frustrated and stall out leading to inaction. Looking back on my life this accurately explains how I&#39;ve arrived at my current spot in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-human-condition&quot;&gt;The human condition &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/#the-human-condition&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While still dazed by his first point he continued his case by showing how the scentific mode is not the mode we commonly use, or can use, in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, this is the human condition. It is life, and our most consequential decisions in life have little or nothing to do with science. This does not mean that we cannot bring rational analysis to bear on the issues. Thoughtful people reflect carefully on important decisions and try to take into account as much evidence as is reasonably available at all times. Nevertheless, rational analysis rarely compels a particular choice and certainly does not guarantee any particular result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had me after describing the problem because it so accurately describes my struggle in life. I was ready to hear how he instead approaches choices during the &amp;quot;normal mode&amp;quot; of life, the vast majority of life. His proposal is that decisions in life are composed of three sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These kinds of questions, which we all face routinely, simply do not submit to scientific solutions. We cannot make one choice and see how the experiment comes out, then rewind the tape and make the other choice to determine the outcome in the alternative scenario. Rather, we have a one-time shot at our most important decisions. We are forced to rely on intuition, on experience, on the advice of friends, on precarious projections into the future, and, in the end, on our gut feelings about what is likely to prove &amp;quot;right&amp;quot; in a given situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He later sums it up nicely stating &amp;quot;normal mode&amp;quot; choices are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the blend of intuition, analysis, and hopeful commitment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/#conclusion&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve heard about the head, heart, and gut triad before and an aim in life is being able to listen to each. To have the three be able to communicate with each other. I like the manner in which Bill Newsome describes this. I need this lesson repeated often. I found his approach refreshing. It has given me renewed motivation to step into this &amp;quot;human condition&amp;quot;, although I still find I am hesitant to say embrace this &amp;quot;human condition&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Reflections on project management</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-reflections-on-project-management/"/>
		<updated>2021-06-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-reflections-on-project-management/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-discussion&quot;&gt;The discussion &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-reflections-on-project-management/#the-discussion&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The saying goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you put 10 economists in a room, you’ll get 11 opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems with project management teams, every team member has their thoughts on how to manage projects. Opinions are plentiful, even amongst team members who share similar roles; although to a lesser extent than those across different roles. Every so often an event will occur or something will be said which once again sparks conversations on how projects should be managed. Much time is then spent discussing everyone&#39;s opinions. Often some minimal change will be made, at least temporarily. But nothing really changes. Everyone still thinks the project isn&#39;t being run well. People give up and surrender to the reality dysfunction. We do what we can but are secretly bitter, thinking how out of whack things are but accept the current state as being inevitable, as we drift closer and closer to the process becoming a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bullshit_Jobs&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Bullshit job.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m on a team which just recently had another round of these conversations. I participated in the discussion by asking questions but kept my opinions to myself. I&#39;ve succumbed to being jaded with the perspective that I&#39;ll mostly have to jump through the hoops others desire. The best hope I have is to try to get through the process as quickly as possible so I can go about the work. This frustrates others on the team because I&#39;m not leading. I willingly contribute but do not step up to volunteer to be the JIRA driver, organizer or retrospective radiator reader, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Voss&quot;&gt;Christopher Voss&#39; book Never Split the Difference&lt;/a&gt;, which I haven&#39;t read, I believe he argues it&#39;s better for one party to give way when there are differences because by compromising neither party gets what they want and so are unhappy. But if one let&#39;s the other have their way then that person still feels good because they are supporing the other. Is that a solution to the project management dilema? One person gets their way and the rest follow? Maybe it would work. Maybe at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if that was an option I wonder if I would take them up on the offer, to volunteer and try implementing my ideal project management vision for the realities of my team. But I find myself hesitant to do so because the probability of my process not being any better is likely. Why take that risk then and face this reality only to lose hope that there is a better way? It&#39;s easier to quietly judge from the sideline. But that is not helpful and by doing so I forfeit the right to voice an opinion. It is better to risk, learn, and grow. Here then are my thoughts for the environment my team operates within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-environment&quot;&gt;The environment &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-reflections-on-project-management/#the-environment&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not have product owners. We do not have anyone to demo to nor perform user acceptance testing. The team receives high level requirements and we are then asked to implement it. We have the ability to ask questions of a business party, but they have their normal job role to perform so interaction is minimal. This limits the possibilities on how the project can be managed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management wants to forecast how long something will take and our progress toward completion. The business user cares about a tool which improves the services they provide. My team wants to know what to build and to build it well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-cannot-change&quot;&gt;What cannot change &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-reflections-on-project-management/#what-cannot-change&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process begins with the business communicating their needs. Mangement determines how their request fits in with the bigger picture of the organization. Negotiations are made between the business and management on what will be delivered and its priority. When the time comes management informs my team of the project we will be working on and what it entails. This portion of the project management process will not change, it is the way the organization functions. Perhaps some day someone in a high level managment position will lead an intiative to structure projects otherwise. But for now this is they way projects operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-proposal&quot;&gt;The proposal &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-reflections-on-project-management/#the-proposal&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The job of my team is to begin breaking down the project into pieces and determine the order of the work. We then start story pointing some of the initial pieces. Implementtation begins once we have initial unknowns discovered, questions answered, spikes completed, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We select the first small chunk of work. The goal should be 5 to 15 work days, but there isn&#39;t a set timebox. It takes however long it takes. Once that work is complete we meet. We then reflect. Original story points and number of days taken are recorded. We review the backlog, add more items, estimate more items. We then determine the next valuable thing and work on that to completion. Reflect, Record. Refine. Repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;outcome&quot;&gt;Outcome &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-reflections-on-project-management/#outcome&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this system mangement can to some extent forecast based on story points given and effort taken for each chunk of work. The chunks of work completed should still mostly deliver business value, so the business can see the application as it progresses, if they have capacity, and feedback can be recevied, even if it&#39;s just a few minutes of sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can management achieve the accurate and precise timeline they truly desire? No. Will the business get the ideal application for their needs? No. Will the my team know what they are building which measures up to the quality they desire? No. But we all seem a bit closer to these goals and the process is much more efficient. Additionally this all seems feasible to implement within the currenty structure of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-06-reflections-on-project-management/#reflection&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out by bringing up the idea of not splitting the difference, that maybe it&#39;s best to let one person decticate how the project is managed. It is not lost on me that my solution has everyone splitting the difference regarding the outcome of the project. If we truly were not to split the difference what would that look like? My team gets to build the perfect project but never deliver it? Mangement dedicates the timeline but ends up with a buggy product and a burnt out team? The business gets a dedicated dev team catering to their every needs but at great expense? Perhaps what&#39;s needed most is acceptance. That the world is messy and we prevail by coming together.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Logging Azure Function App log entries using Serilog gotchas</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-azure-function-logging-with-serilog/"/>
		<updated>2021-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-azure-function-logging-with-serilog/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The problem &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-azure-function-logging-with-serilog/#the-problem&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azure Functions are great, except logging configuration is not the same as .Net Core applications and there are a number of ways logging can be configured incorrectly which leads to unexpected behavior. One such scenario I recently experienced was sending the Function App logs to Serilog. This was accomplished in start up using the &lt;code&gt;AddLogging&lt;/code&gt; extension method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-csharp&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-csharp&quot;&gt;Log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logger &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constructor-invocation class-name&quot;&gt;LoggerConfiguration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;WriteTo&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;Console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;CreateLogger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;builder&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Services&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;AddSingleton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logger&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;AddLogging&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;loggingBuilder &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&gt;&lt;/span&gt; loggingBuilder&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;AddSerilog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token named-parameter punctuation&quot;&gt;dispose&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token boolean&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seemingly worked. Maybe. There appeared to be missing log entries at times, they never made it to the sink, so maybe not. This was not investigated further because what we did find was the Function App Information level logging is noisy. We therefore adjusted the log level by updating &lt;code&gt;host.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-json&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-json&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;&quot;logging&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;&quot;default&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;Warning&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this didn&#39;t seem to make any impact. Function App Information level logs were still being written to the sink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-resolution&quot;&gt;The resolution &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-azure-function-logging-with-serilog/#the-resolution&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a question similar to the problem we experience posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/a/67225369&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow with a helpful answer&lt;/a&gt;. The reason is not clear, just hints and warnings about when and how logging is used in start up. Instead of using the &lt;code&gt;AddLogging&lt;/code&gt; extension method registering an &lt;code&gt;ILoggerProvider&lt;/code&gt; is suggested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-csharp&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-csharp&quot;&gt;Log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logger &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constructor-invocation class-name&quot;&gt;LoggerConfiguration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;WriteTo&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;Console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;CreateLogger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;builder&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Services&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;AddSingleton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logger&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token generic-method&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;AddSingleton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token generic class-name&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;ILoggingProvider&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constructor-invocation class-name&quot;&gt;Serilog&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Extensions&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logging&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;SerilogLoggerProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logger&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token named-parameter punctuation&quot;&gt;dispose&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token boolean&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This worked as expected! Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/users/6345585/martin-cerny&quot;&gt;Martin Cerny&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-problem&quot;&gt;Next problem &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-azure-function-logging-with-serilog/#next-problem&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Function App logging was no longer noisy, but sometimes it is nice to change the log level and receive lower level log entries. How can this be accomplished without deploying a new version of the Function App?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-solution&quot;&gt;Next solution &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-azure-function-logging-with-serilog/#next-solution&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azure Functions provide a convenient way of &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-functions/functions-host-json#override-hostjson-values&quot;&gt;overriding values in the host file&lt;/a&gt;. We can therefore use this mechanism to change the log level by adding an Application Setting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;AzureFunctionsJobHost__logging__default: Information
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We once again receive Information level events coming from the Function App. The one drawback to this is that the Function App will be restarted when an Application Setting is added or changed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The path to empathy is self reflection</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-empathy-through-self-reflection/"/>
		<updated>2021-05-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-empathy-through-self-reflection/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-empathy-through-self-reflection/#story&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other night a group I&#39;ve joined at times was reading through the Bible. I have participated in such groups in the past. This group feels and functions very similarly to the others. It begins with small talk along with beverages. Then an opening prayer to kick things off followed by scripture reading and discussion. Prayer requests and a time of prayer follows. Then small talk resumes again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This group is reading through the Gospel of Mark. This night we were looking at chapter 7. It begins with Jesus and his disciples eating with unwashed hands. The religious elite of the day saw this as a major failure and questioned Jesus about it. Jesus let them have it, teaching that the defilement to be most concerned about is what comes from within us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group commented on the story, sharing as you might expect, such as the culture of the day and the failure of the religious to miss the forest for the trees, but never venturing into asking questions of ourselves. What do we hold to which we are concerned is defiling but all the while ignoring what is within us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-empathy-through-self-reflection/#reflection&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sense is we are proud of ourselves. That we are beyond those we rail about. Even beyond those other Christian groups. But are we really? It feels we all are the same thing differently. Yes, there are great variances in Christian groups, but we also share similarities, such as being formulaic. I suppose it&#39;s natural, only human. But I wonder how closely we compare to those we think ourselves better than. Wash you hands feels the same as read scripture, discuss, pray. But the question of defilement was missed. The question of ourselves is missed. We are those we think we&#39;re better than. Anger rises within me. But I also have hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal&quot;&gt;Proposal &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-empathy-through-self-reflection/#proposal&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope is that when we realize this it will lead us to real empathy. Forgiveness comes more easily when we see how the gap between us has been bridged. Instead of further division it brings unity. The differences between us, between groups, are real but that doesn&#39;t mean divisions are the result. And I found that as I was sitting there in that group I felt superior to them because they weren&#39;t reflecting on themselves, and they were thinking themselves superior to those in the story. But that was exact same thing I was doing to them. Upon my realization of this the gap I had created between me and that group had been bridged. My self reflection lead to empathy. And so I have hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Absent mindedness. Lost in thought. Automatic processing.</title>
		<link href="https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/"/>
		<updated>2021-05-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/#story&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driving back from a social engagement with my girlfriend to her house I was reflecting on our time there. We were driving down neighborhood streets in an area I hadn&#39;t been previously. When we got to her street I kept going straight, after which she alerted me I missed the turn. This brought about a new set of questions for my mind to consider such as: why didn&#39;t recognize her street? How many other things was as oblivious to as I drove that night? What is the threat of danger while thinking? What is she thinking about me that I didn&#39;t recognize her street? How much do I care about each of these questions? And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to her place I started to collect my things to head home. I felt I had fewer things than when I arrived, so I started to survey my list of items. I realized why I had fewer items, prepared my dog for leaving and was ready to depart, at which time she asked if I had grabbed the items she picked up for me at Costco earlier that day. No. No I had not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/#backstory&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I experienced a number of memory misses that day. It felt defeating. Why was this? They seem to occur more frequently these recent years in midlife. I took pride in my memory when I was young. I unfortunately relied on it through my school years to get me through most classes without putting in much effort and learning the material. About two years I started experiencing sleep difficulties. All areas of my life were impacted, including my mind. I began noticing memory issues at that time. While trying to determine the reason for my sleep issues I took a number of psychological in an attempt to better understand how my brain was functioning. The results revealed that in all areas my brain functioned very well, except for my working memory. The results confirmed what I was already thinking. It was a question in my mind whether this decline was due to lack of sleep or a natural occurrence of age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/#reflection&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driving home another thought occurred to me. What if these memories issues aren&#39;t always issues. Maybe we chalk it up to absent mindedness but that&#39;s not really what&#39;s going on. Being lost in thought and not devoting your attention to the present surroundings must account for some of this. Someone who spends much time in thought this felt comforting. But I always lived in my head. Perhaps when I was young I was able to devote mental resources to both my internal world and the external world. That I had the mental flexibility to quickly jump back and forth between them. This is perhaps a result of having reduced working memory capabilities. But the more intriguing possibility for apparent absent mindedness is automatic processing. Automatic pilot. As we age has our brain able to shift more everyday items to automatic processing, which has the undesirable consequence of causing us to miss all those little things which are not a part of this processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal&quot;&gt;Proposal &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.christopherlopes.com/posts/2021-05-absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/#proposal&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listen to a couple neroscience podcasts and have read a couple pop-neroscience books but have not devoted study to the topic. My understanding is that our brains attempt to make its processing efficient. When it faces something new it takes place in one part of the brain, and we need to devote our attention to it. But once we become familiar with the task our brains shift it over to an automatic processing area. And thankfully so! Devoting attention to all the things we&#39;ve learned in life we would quickly be at our functioning limit. As we age we build up more and more of this automatic routines. But these routines are not perfect. And because we are not focusing our attention things will be missed. Mistakes will be made. Items will be forgotten, therefore maybe our apparent absent mindedness is not a memory issue but an indication of the beauty of our mind. And instead of the feeling of embarrassment and discouragement we can proudly trumpet these experiences show casing the number of routines we have amassed into automatic processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strike&gt;Absent mindedness&lt;/strike&gt; Automatic processing&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
