<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Figuring \w+ out</title>
	<subtitle></subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://ciwchris.github.io/blog"/>
	<updated>2021-06-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://ciwchris.github.io/blog</id>
	<author>
		<name>Christopher Lopes</name>
		<email>christopher.lopes@pm.me</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Science is peculiar in decision-making</title>
		<link href="https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/"/>
		<updated>2021-06-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-prompt&quot;&gt;The prompt &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/#the-prompt&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggle to make decisions and therefore whenever coming across material on the topic I take note. Recently I was listening to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://biologos.org/podcast-episodes/bill-newsome-neuroscience-faith-free-will&quot;&gt;Language of God podcast with Bill Newsome.&lt;/a&gt; in which they discussed a paper he wrote in 2010, &lt;a href=&quot;https://biologos.org/podcast-episodes/bill-newsome-neuroscience-faith-free-will&quot;&gt;Life of science, life of faith.&lt;/a&gt; Both the podcast and the paper are interesting and so worth the listen and read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;science-is-peculiar&quot;&gt;Science is peculiar &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/#science-is-peculiar&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two points in particular which stood out to me while listening to the podcast which motivated me to read the paper. The first addresses a question he often receives from his colleague concerning the apparent inconsistent approach between the way he approaches his scientific work and his religious life. In the paper he writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both my colleague and my postdoc were struck by the apparent inconsistency in my adoption of religious beliefs without similarly rigorous standards of proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reply is that, yes, the modes of thought in the two domains can be quite different. This is one of the genuine points of tension between science and religion. Importantly, however, the mode that predominates in religious life is the normal mode of evaluation and decision-making in the overall context of human experience. The scientific mode, in contrast, is quite peculiar: it is applicable to a rather narrow range of experience and is generally practiced by a rather small community of professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me this was a moment of enlightenment. I attempt to bring a scientific approach to everything in my life but I struggle greatly to do so. I do not trust my intuition. I do not trust my emotions. I often sink lots of time trying to understand what to think, feel, or do in all areas of my life. I become frustrated and stall out leading to inaction. Looking back on my life this accurately explains how I&#39;ve arrived at my current spot in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-human-condition&quot;&gt;The human condition &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/#the-human-condition&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While still dazed by his first point he continued his case by showing how the scentific mode is not the mode we commonly use, or can use, in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, this is the human condition. It is life, and our most consequential decisions in life have little or nothing to do with science. This does not mean that we cannot bring rational analysis to bear on the issues. Thoughtful people reflect carefully on important decisions and try to take into account as much evidence as is reasonably available at all times. Nevertheless, rational analysis rarely compels a particular choice and certainly does not guarantee any particular result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had me after describing the problem because it so accurately describes my struggle in life. I was ready to hear how he instead approaches choices during the &amp;quot;normal mode&amp;quot; of life, the vast majority of life. His proposal is that decisions in life are composed of three sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These kinds of questions, which we all face routinely, simply do not submit to scientific solutions. We cannot make one choice and see how the experiment comes out, then rewind the tape and make the other choice to determine the outcome in the alternative scenario. Rather, we have a one-time shot at our most important decisions. We are forced to rely on intuition, on experience, on the advice of friends, on precarious projections into the future, and, in the end, on our gut feelings about what is likely to prove &amp;quot;right&amp;quot; in a given situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He later sums it up nicely stating &amp;quot;normal mode&amp;quot; choices are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the blend of intuition, analysis, and hopeful commitment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/science-is-peculiar-in-decision-making/#conclusion&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve heard about the head, heart, and gut triad before and an aim in life is being able to listen to each. To have the three be able to communicate with each other. I like the manner in which Bill Newsome describes this. I need this lesson repeated often. I found his approach refreshing. It has given me renewed motivation to step into this &amp;quot;human condition&amp;quot;, although I still find I am hesitant to say embrace this &amp;quot;human condition&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Reflections on project management 2021</title>
		<link href="https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/reflections-on-project-management-2021/"/>
		<updated>2021-06-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/reflections-on-project-management-2021/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-discussion&quot;&gt;The discussion &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/reflections-on-project-management-2021/#the-discussion&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The saying goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you put 10 economists in a room, you’ll get 11 opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems with project management teams, every team member has their thoughts on how to manage projects. Opinions are plentiful, even amongst team members who share similar roles; although to a lesser extent than those across different roles. Every so often an event will occur or something will be said which once again sparks conversations on how projects should be managed. Much time is then spent discussing everyone&#39;s opinions. Often some minimal change will be made, at least temporarily. But nothing really changes. Everyone still thinks the project isn&#39;t being run well. People give up and surrender to the reality dysfunction. We do what we can but are secretly bitter, thinking how out of whack things are but accept the current state as being inevitable, as we drift closer and closer to the process becoming a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bullshit_Jobs&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Bullshit job.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m on a team which just recently had another round of these conversations. I participated in the discussion by asking questions but kept my opinions to myself. I&#39;ve succumbed to being jaded with the perspective that I&#39;ll mostly have to jump through the hoops others desire. The best hope I have is to try to get through the process as quickly as possible so I can go about the work. This frustrates others on the team because I&#39;m not leading. I willingly contribute but do not step up to volunteer to be the JIRA driver, organizer or retrospective radiator reader, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Voss&quot;&gt;Christopher Voss&#39; book Never Split the Difference&lt;/a&gt;, which I haven&#39;t read, I believe he argues it&#39;s better for one party to give way when there are differences because by compromising neither party gets what they want and so are unhappy. But if one let&#39;s the other have their way then that person still feels good because they are supporing the other. Is that a solution to the project management dilema? One person gets their way and the rest follow? Maybe it would work. Maybe at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if that was an option I wonder if I would take them up on the offer, to volunteer and try implementing my ideal project management vision for the realities of my team. But I find myself hesitant to do so because the probability of my process not being any better is likely. Why take that risk then and face this reality only to lose hope that there is a better way? It&#39;s easier to quietly judge from the sideline. But that is not helpful and by doing so I forfeit the right to voice an opinion. It is better to risk, learn, and grow. Here then are my thoughts for the environment my team operates within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-environment&quot;&gt;The environment &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/reflections-on-project-management-2021/#the-environment&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not have product owners. We do not have anyone to demo to nor perform user acceptance testing. The team receives high level requirements and we are then asked to implement it. We have the ability to ask questions of a business party, but they have their normal job role to perform so interaction is minimal. This limits the possibilities on how the project can be managed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management wants to forecast how long something will take and our progress toward completion. The business user cares about a tool which improves the services they provide. My team wants to know what to build and to build it well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-cannot-change&quot;&gt;What cannot change &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/reflections-on-project-management-2021/#what-cannot-change&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process begins with the business communicating their needs. Mangement determines how their request fits in with the bigger picture of the organization. Negotiations are made between the business and management on what will be delivered and its priority. When the time comes management informs my team of the project we will be working on and what it entails. This portion of the project management process will not change, it is the way the organization functions. Perhaps some day someone in a high level managment position will lead an intiative to structure projects otherwise. But for now this is they way projects operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-proposal&quot;&gt;The proposal &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/reflections-on-project-management-2021/#the-proposal&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The job of my team is to begin breaking down the project into pieces and determine the order of the work. We then start story pointing some of the initial pieces. Implementtation begins once we have initial unknowns discovered, questions answered, spikes completed, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We select the first small chunk of work. The goal should be 5 to 15 work days, but there isn&#39;t a set timebox. It takes however long it takes. Once that work is complete we meet. We then reflect. Original story points and number of days taken are recorded. We review the backlog, add more items, estimate more items. We then determine the next valuable thing and work on that to completion. Reflect, Record. Refine. Repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;outcome&quot;&gt;Outcome &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/reflections-on-project-management-2021/#outcome&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this system mangement can to some extent forecast based on story points given and effort taken for each chunk of work. The chunks of work completed should still mostly deliver business value, so the business can see the application as it progresses, if they have capacity, and feedback can be recevied, even if it&#39;s just a few minutes of sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can management achieve the accurate and precise timeline they truly desire? No. Will the business get the ideal application for their needs? No. Will the my team know what they are building which measures up to the quality they desire? No. But we all seem a bit closer to these goals and the process is much more efficient. Additionally this all seems feasible to implement within the currenty structure of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/reflections-on-project-management-2021/#reflection&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out by bringing up the idea of not splitting the difference, that maybe it&#39;s best to let one person decticate how the project is managed. It is not lost on me that my solution has everyone splitting the difference regarding the outcome of the project. If we truly were not to split the difference what would that look like? My team gets to build the perfect project but never deliver it? Mangement dedicates the timeline but ends up with a buggy product and a burnt out team? The business gets a dedicated dev team catering to their every needs but at great expense? Perhaps what&#39;s needed most is acceptance. That the world is messy and we prevail by coming together.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Logging Azure Function App log entries using Serilog gotchas</title>
		<link href="https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/azure-function-logging-with-serilog/"/>
		<updated>2021-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/azure-function-logging-with-serilog/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The problem &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/azure-function-logging-with-serilog/#the-problem&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azure Functions are great, except logging configuration is not the same as .Net Core applications and there are a number of ways logging can be configured incorrectly which leads to unexpected behavior. One such scenario I recently experienced was sending the Function App logs to Serilog. This was accomplished in start up using the &lt;code&gt;AddLogging&lt;/code&gt; extension method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-csharp&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-csharp&quot;&gt;Log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logger &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constructor-invocation class-name&quot;&gt;LoggerConfiguration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;WriteTo&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;Console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;CreateLogger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;builder&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Services&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;AddSingleton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logger&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;AddLogging&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;loggingBuilder &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&gt;&lt;/span&gt; loggingBuilder&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;AddSerilog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token named-parameter punctuation&quot;&gt;dispose&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token boolean&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seemingly worked. Maybe. There appeared to be missing log entries at times, they never made it to the sink, so maybe not. This was not investigated further because what we did find was the Function App Information level logging is noisy. We therefore adjusted the log level by updating &lt;code&gt;host.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-json&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-json&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;&quot;logging&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;&quot;default&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;Warning&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this didn&#39;t seem to make any impact. Function App Information level logs were still being written to the sink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-resolution&quot;&gt;The resolution &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/azure-function-logging-with-serilog/#the-resolution&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a question similar to the problem we experience posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/a/67225369&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow with a helpful answer&lt;/a&gt;. The reason is not clear, just hints and warnings about when and how logging is used in start up. Instead of using the &lt;code&gt;AddLogging&lt;/code&gt; extension method registering an &lt;code&gt;ILoggerProvider&lt;/code&gt; is suggested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-csharp&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-csharp&quot;&gt;Log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logger &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constructor-invocation class-name&quot;&gt;LoggerConfiguration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;WriteTo&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;Console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;CreateLogger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;builder&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Services&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;AddSingleton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logger&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token generic-method&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;AddSingleton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token generic class-name&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;ILoggingProvider&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constructor-invocation class-name&quot;&gt;Serilog&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Extensions&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logging&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;SerilogLoggerProvider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Log&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;Logger&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token named-parameter punctuation&quot;&gt;dispose&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token boolean&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This worked as expected! Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/users/6345585/martin-cerny&quot;&gt;Martin Cerny&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-problem&quot;&gt;Next problem &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/azure-function-logging-with-serilog/#next-problem&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Function App logging was no longer noisy, but sometimes it is nice to change the log level and receive lower level log entries. How can this be accomplished without deploying a new version of the Function App?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-solution&quot;&gt;Next solution &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/azure-function-logging-with-serilog/#next-solution&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azure Functions provide a convenient way of &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-functions/functions-host-json#override-hostjson-values&quot;&gt;overriding values in the host file&lt;/a&gt;. We can therefore use this mechanism to change the log level by adding an Application Setting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;AzureFunctionsJobHost__logging__default: Information
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We once again receive Information level events coming from the Function App. The one drawback to this is that the Function App will be restarted when an Application Setting is added or changed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The path to empathy is self reflection</title>
		<link href="https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/empathy-through-self-reflection/"/>
		<updated>2021-05-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/empathy-through-self-reflection/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/empathy-through-self-reflection/#story&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other night a group I&#39;ve joined at times was reading through the Bible. I have participated in such groups in the past. This group feels and functions very similarly to the others. It begins with small talk along with beverages. Then an opening prayer to kick things off followed by scripture reading and discussion. Prayer requests and a time of prayer follows. Then small talk resumes again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This group is reading through the Gospel of Mark. This night we were looking at chapter 7. It begins with Jesus and his disciples eating with unwashed hands. The religious elite of the day saw this as a major failure and questioned Jesus about it. Jesus let them have it, teaching that the defilement to be most concerned about is what comes from within us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group commented on the story, sharing as you might expect, such as the culture of the day and the failure of the religious to miss the forest for the trees, but never venturing into asking questions of ourselves. What do we hold to which we are concerned is defiling but all the while ignoring what is within us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/empathy-through-self-reflection/#reflection&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sense is we are proud of ourselves. That we are beyond those we rail about. Even beyond those other Christian groups. But are we really? It feels we all are the same thing differently. Yes, there are great variances in Christian groups, but we also share similarities, such as being formulaic. I suppose it&#39;s natural, only human. But I wonder how closely we compare to those we think ourselves better than. Wash you hands feels the same as read scripture, discuss, pray. But the question of defilement was missed. The question of ourselves is missed. We are those we think we&#39;re better than. Anger rises within me. But I also have hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal&quot;&gt;Proposal &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/empathy-through-self-reflection/#proposal&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope is that when we realize this it will lead us to real empathy. Forgiveness comes more easily when we see how the gap between us has been bridged. Instead of further division it brings unity. The differences between us, between groups, are real but that doesn&#39;t mean divisions are the result. And I found that as I was sitting there in that group I felt superior to them because they weren&#39;t reflecting on themselves, and they were thinking themselves superior to those in the story. But that was exact same thing I was doing to them. Upon my realization of this the gap I had created between me and that group had been bridged. My self reflection lead to empathy. And so I have hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Absent mindedness. Lost in thought. Automatic processing.</title>
		<link href="https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/"/>
		<updated>2021-05-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/#story&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driving back from a social engagement with my girlfriend to her house I was reflecting on our time there. We were driving down neighborhood streets in an area I hadn&#39;t been previously. When we got to her street I kept going straight, after which she alerted me I missed the turn. This brought about a new set of questions for my mind to consider such as: why didn&#39;t recognize her street? How many other things was as oblivious to as I drove that night? What is the threat of danger while thinking? What is she thinking about me that I didn&#39;t recognize her street? How much do I care about each of these questions? And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to her place I started to collect my things to head home. I felt I had fewer things than when I arrived, so I started to survey my list of items. I realized why I had fewer items, prepared my dog for leaving and was ready to depart, at which time she asked if I had grabbed the items she picked up for me at Costco earlier that day. No. No I had not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/#backstory&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I experienced a number of memory misses that day. It felt defeating. Why was this? They seem to occur more frequently these recent years in midlife. I took pride in my memory when I was young. I unfortunately relied on it through my school years to get me through most classes without putting in much effort and learning the material. About two years I started experiencing sleep difficulties. All areas of my life were impacted, including my mind. I began noticing memory issues at that time. While trying to determine the reason for my sleep issues I took a number of psychological in an attempt to better understand how my brain was functioning. The results revealed that in all areas my brain functioned very well, except for my working memory. The results confirmed what I was already thinking. It was a question in my mind whether this decline was due to lack of sleep or a natural occurrence of age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/#reflection&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driving home another thought occurred to me. What if these memories issues aren&#39;t always issues. Maybe we chalk it up to absent mindedness but that&#39;s not really what&#39;s going on. Being lost in thought and not devoting your attention to the present surroundings must account for some of this. Someone who spends much time in thought this felt comforting. But I always lived in my head. Perhaps when I was young I was able to devote mental resources to both my internal world and the external world. That I had the mental flexibility to quickly jump back and forth between them. This is perhaps a result of having reduced working memory capabilities. But the more intriguing possibility for apparent absent mindedness is automatic processing. Automatic pilot. As we age has our brain able to shift more everyday items to automatic processing, which has the undesirable consequence of causing us to miss all those little things which are not a part of this processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal&quot;&gt;Proposal &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://ciwchris.github.io/blog/posts/absent-mindedness-automatic-processing/#proposal&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listen to a couple neroscience podcasts and have read a couple pop-neroscience books but have not devoted study to the topic. My understanding is that our brains attempt to make its processing efficient. When it faces something new it takes place in one part of the brain, and we need to devote our attention to it. But once we become familiar with the task our brains shift it over to an automatic processing area. And thankfully so! Devoting attention to all the things we&#39;ve learned in life we would quickly be at our functioning limit. As we age we build up more and more of this automatic routines. But these routines are not perfect. And because we are not focusing our attention things will be missed. Mistakes will be made. Items will be forgotten, therefore maybe our apparent absent mindedness is not a memory issue but an indication of the beauty of our mind. And instead of the feeling of embarrassment and discouragement we can proudly trumpet these experiences show casing the number of routines we have amassed into automatic processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strike&gt;Absent mindedness&lt;/strike&gt; Automatic processing&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
